<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Laboratory of wheat abiotic stress tolerance</title>
    <link>/</link>
      <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Laboratory of wheat abiotic stress tolerance</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu632e353c6447b34a07d412b7f995aeea_7708_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Laboratory of wheat abiotic stress tolerance</title>
      <link>/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation :Xiangjun Lai</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_20_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_20_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Genome-wide association study dissect the genetic basis of grain quality in bread wheat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation :Yijin Chen</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_20_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_20_3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Differences of overexpression of COL and GSNOR in seed setting under stress.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation :Zihui Liu</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_20_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_20_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Selection and application of loci to regulate the peduncle length in wheat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation :Shaowei Yang</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_19_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_19_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Selection of dwarf gene in natural population of wheat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation :Yuanfei Zhang</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_19_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_19_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Selection of vernalization and photoperiod genes in natural populations of wheat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation :Mingzhu Chen </title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_18_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_18_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Genome-wide association analysis identified genes that regulate root development.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation :Wenyang hou</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_18_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_18_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Phenotypic observation of EMS mutant in wheat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation :Shuyang Sun</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_17_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_17_3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Genotypes of TaGSK3 functional loss mutants Identification and phenotypic observation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation :Xiangzheng Chai</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_17_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_17_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Eda40D is a genetic suppressor of rad23b.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation :Zhiwei Zhu</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_17_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_17_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Randomized t-test for phenotypic data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation :Pengcheng Wang</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_16_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_16_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Preliminary mapping of QTL for nitrogen use efficiency in Wheat Seedlings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation :Rong Xue</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_16_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_16_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Differentiation of alternative splicing responses to abiotic stress in wheat subgenomes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation : Ruirui Mo</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_15_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_15_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The Effects of Early Leaf Senescence on Wheat Yield.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation : Xiuyun Ma</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_15_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_15_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Mapping of genes for total root length and root surface area of wheat at seedling stage based on gene-wide association analysis and development of molecular markers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation : Peng Zhao</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_14_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_14_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Large Scale RNA-seq Identify Genes and Genetic Network Involved in Root Development of Bread Wheat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation : Zunkai Hu</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_14_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_14_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Functional Analysis of Single Nucleotide Polymorphism (SNP) Variation in Natural Populations of Wheat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation : Jialiang Zhang</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_13_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_13_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The Molecular Mechanism of TaGSK3 mediated BR and IAA Signaling Pathways Regulating Lateral Root Development in Wheat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation : Xiaolong Guo</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_13_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_13_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Molecular mechanism of TaGSK3 regulating wheat plant architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation : Xiangjun Lai</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_12_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_12_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Genome-wide association study dissect the genetic basis of grain quality in bread wheat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation : Zihui Liu</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_12_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_12_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The peduncle length selection in bread wheat modern breeding.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xiaolong Guo received the accessit for excellence</title>
      <link>/talk/news_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/news_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Main Content:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
On March 5, 2022, the second postgraduate academic forum was held at the International Exchange Center by the Graduate School, the Graduate Work Department of the Party Committee, the State Key Laboratory of Soil Erosion and Dryland Agriculture on the Loess Plateau and the State Key Laboratory of Crop Stress Biology in Arid Regions. Room 104 went smoothly.&lt;br/&gt;
Hao Feng, director of the Institute of Soil and Water Conservation, presided over the opening ceremony, and Zhang Chaoyang, executive deputy director of the Dry Farming Department, introduced the preparation and selection methods for the forum. Afterwards, 16 postgraduates who stood out after screening at various levels in the previous stage reported on their research topics.&lt;br/&gt;
Xiaolong Guo, a doctoral student in the research group, participated in this forum. With the theme of &amp;ldquo;Gene Function Analysis Reveals How Natural Mutations of TaGSK3 Gene Are Selected by Environment&amp;rdquo;, he introduced the gene function of natural mutants of TaGSK3 gene in simple terms, and proposed the natural mutation of TaGSK3 gene. A conjecture chosen by the environment. The whole report was eloquent and interesting, which aroused heated discussions between the judges and the audience.&lt;br/&gt;
In the end, Xiaolong Guo won the second prize of the second postgraduate academic forum of the two state key laboratories after the evaluation, discussion and selection of the expert group. This award shows Guo Xiaolong&amp;rsquo;s solid scientific research foundation and meticulous logical thinking, as well as the pragmatic and meticulous demeanor of the graduate students of the research group.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation : Bingxin Shi</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_11_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_11_3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Functional analysis of TaABA8oxs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation : Tian Lu</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_11_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_11_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Establishment and utilization of a rapid screening strategy of natural BR mutants in bread wheat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation : Yijin Chen</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_11_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_11_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Genome-wide association study of spike fertility and yield components in common wheat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yanli Feng, breeder of dryland wheat variety -- &#39;Tongmai&#39; series, was invited to have a discussion on how to choose employment for postgraduates.</title>
      <link>/talk/social_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/social_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Expert Profile:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Yanli Feng, female, senior agronomist, is currently the deputy head of the Yaozhou District People&amp;rsquo;s Government of Tongchuan City and the deputy chairman
of the Tongchuan Municipal Committee of the Democratic National Construction Association. Since 1991, he has been engaged in wheat breeding and technology
promotion in the front line of agricultural production. He participated in the breeding of &amp;lsquo;Tongmai No. 1-3&amp;rsquo; series of dryland wheat varieties, and presided
over the breeding of &amp;lsquo;Tongmai No. 4-6&amp;rsquo; series of dryland wheat varieties. He has presided over and participated in 24 provincial and municipal scientific
research and technology promotion projects, of which four won the Municipal Science and Technology Progress Award issued by the municipal government, and five
won the Provincial Science and Technology Promotion and Progress Award issued by the provincial government, and were rated as outstanding in Tongchuan City.
Contributed top-notch talents and winner of the &amp;ldquo;May 4th&amp;rdquo; Youth Medal in Shaanxi Province.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;b&gt;forum:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
On February 25, 2022, Yanli Feng, a breeder of the dryland wheat variety &amp;lsquo;Tongmai&amp;rsquo; series, came to the research group to have a discussion and exchange
on how graduate students should choose jobs and find employment. All graduate students in the laboratory participated in the discussion.&lt;br/&gt;
At the symposium, Feng Yanli carefully shared her study and work experience, and provided three valuable experiences to the students: First,
always cherish the thirst for knowledge, maintain a progressive heart, be full of thirst for knowledge, and constantly motivate yourself 2.
We must do well the seemingly complicated, subtle and ordinary daily work, exercise our confidence and patience with priorities, work hard for
a long time in the process of thinking, exploration, and summarization, improve day by day, and strive for early accumulation. Think, improve
emotional intelligence, if you want to win the respect of others, you must first know how to respect others. If you want to be warm and kind,
you must first learn to treat people with sincerity.&lt;br/&gt;
Afterwards, the students had a more in-depth exchange with Feng Yanli about their career and employment confusion. There were heated discussions
around &amp;lsquo;how to choose a work direction&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;how to choose a work place&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;how to define a job as a career to pursue in a lifetime&amp;rsquo;. Ma Xiuyun,
a 2019 graduate student, said happily: &amp;lsquo;The communication with Mr. Feng was like a timely spring rain, which blew away the &amp;lsquo;smog&amp;rsquo; I faced in
choosing a career. Now I am more clear about what career choice I should make.&amp;rsquo; Sun Shuyang, a graduate student, said: &amp;lsquo;Thanks to Mr. Feng for
his valuable advice on employment issues, which allowed me to determine the goals of my postgraduate studies and provide direction for my future
study and work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shaanxi Datang Seed Industry Co., Ltd. came to for a discussion on deepening scientific and technological cooperation with us.</title>
      <link>/talk/social_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/social_3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
On February 24, 2022, Chairman Jianjun Bu and Director Shuping Bian of Shaanxi Datang Seed Industry Co., Ltd. came to the research group to have a discussion
on deepening agricultural science and technology cooperation. Professor Shengbao Xu, the head of the research group, met with Jianjun Bu , Shuping Bian ,
doctoral students Zihui Liu, Xiaolong Guo, Peng Zhao and postgraduate Tian Lu for a discussion.&lt;br/&gt;
At the meeting, Shuping Bian introduced the school-site cooperation and technical requirements, and expressed his gratitude to the research group for
its strong support to Shaanxi Datang Seed Industry Co., Ltd. It is hoped that relying on the intellectual resources such as technology and talents of the
research group, it can help Shaanxi Datang Seed Industry Co., Ltd. cultivate new germplasm resources and promote the further development of the company.
Shaanxi Datang Seed Industry Co., Ltd. will also continue to actively optimize the form of cooperation, fully cooperate with the research group in the
construction and maintenance of the industry-university-research cooperation platform and talent training cooperation platform, and promote the integrated
development of schools, enterprises, and industry, academia, and research to achieve mutual benefit and win-win results.&lt;br/&gt;
Professor Shengbao Xu thanked Shaanxi Datang Seed Industry Co., Ltd. for its concern and support to the research group. He said that Shaanxi Datang Seed
Industry Co., Ltd. is an important platform for the integration and cooperation of production, education and research for the research group. Subsequently,
Zihui Liu, Xiaolong Guo, Peng Zhao and Tian Lu introduced the current research directions and research progress of the research group, and expounded the forms
and development potential of cooperation with enterprises in different research directions. He also pointed out that only by organically combining technology
and industry and doing &amp;lsquo;useful scientific research&amp;rsquo; can the story of a wheat seed be told well. The research group will actively utilize the advantages of
agricultural technology and talents to boost the development of Shaanxi Datang Seed Industry Co., Ltd. and ultimately achieve a win-win situation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation : Rong Xue</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_1_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_1_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
variable cut in wheat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation : Peng Zhao</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_1_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_1_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Peng Zhao reported the recent analysis results. Using GWAS analysis, a QTL locus regulating root development was identified on chromosome 6A, KASP marker was developed, and the reliability of this locus was verified by RIL population.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation : Xiuyun Ma</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_2_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_2_3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In this group meeting, Ma Xiuyun mainly reported the following two parts: &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Haplotype analysis of natural populations;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;QTL analysis of root phenotype.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation : Xiangjun Lai</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_2_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_2_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The recent genome-wide association analysis results of wheat quality traits have deepened the understanding of the environmental variation of wheat quality traits.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation : Zihui Liu</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_2_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_2_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The GWAS of Plant height and Peduncle height.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation : Pengcheng Wang</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_3_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_3_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Pengcheng Wang reported the relevant results of the effect of TaGSK on nitrogen absorption.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation : Ruirui Mo</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_4_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_4_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Ruirui Mo reported the research progress of using CRISPR/Cas9 technology to study the effect of wheat genes on wheat grain traits.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sun Miao, a postdoctor from Aarhus University, Denmark, was invited to attend our research symposium.</title>
      <link>/talk/social_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/social_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Expert Profile:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Miao Sun, male, graduated from the Institute of Botany, Chinese Academy of Sciences with a Ph.D., and worked as a postdoctoral fellow and visiting scholar at the School of Ecology and Evolutionary Biology at the University of Michigan and the Florida Museum of Natural History at the University of Florida. Postdoc at the Center for Information and Biodiversity. The current research direction is to collect and integrate biotic and abiotic big data, and comprehensively apply comparative biology methods; combine big data and phylogenetic relationship to explore the macroevolution of angiosperms and the response mechanism to global change, mainly focusing on species phylogenetic diversity, diversification The spatial and temporal patterns of plant functional (or key) traits evolution in response to environmental changes. Participated in the phylogenetic reconstruction of global seed plants in cooperation with Denmark and the United States; the research on geohistorical constraints, local adaptation and interspecific interactions of the formation of forest communities with discontinuous distribution in East Asia and North America in cooperation with Dimension; the phylogeny of plants in the Gulf of Mexico Reconstruction; Reconstruction of &amp;ldquo;Tree of Life&amp;rdquo;; Phylogenetic study of COM clades of roses; Reconstruction of phylogenetic relationships at the genus level of Chinese vascular plants and many other domestic and foreign projects. At present, he has published 30 papers in Nature, Nature Communications, Science Advances, The ISME Journal and other journals, with a total of 878 Google Scholar citations, and participated in the compilation of 5 chronicles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation : Mingzhu Cheng</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_5_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_5_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Through this period of study, Mingzhu Cheng has been well integrated into the research group. In the first group meeting, she reported on the learning content and insights since she entered school. She deeply realized that we must take everything seriously, no matter what we do. Think carefully, arrange your daily work reasonably in advance, prepare well before the experiment, and be patient and meticulous when doing the experiment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation : Wenyang Hou</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_6_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_6_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In her first group meeting, Wenyang Hou shared some of her achievements since she entered the school. The study in the laboratory made her understand that there are often variables in the experimental process. She believes that experiments are not done overnight and require rigor and patience. In addition, we should read more relevant literature on the subject and improve our professional ability.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation : Shuyang Sun</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_6_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_6_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
As a first-year freshman, Shuyang Sun&amp;rsquo;s first group meeting reported the learning content since the beginning of the school, and gave an overview of the learning situation of the experimental part and the student letter. The experimental part mainly includes the test of the GWAS population in the laboratory, the observation of the root system of wheat seedlings, and the identification of transgenes. And the basic introduction of python language, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruirui Mo, a master student, has been awarded the 2021 National Scholarship.</title>
      <link>/talk/news_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/news_4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Main Content:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
According to the spirit of the school&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Notice on Doing a Good Job in the Selection of Various Scholarships
for Graduate Students in the 2021-2022 Academic Year&amp;rsquo; and the &amp;lsquo;Implementation Rules for the Evaluation of
Postgraduate Scholarships for the 2021-2022 Academic Year of the Agricultural College&amp;rsquo;, the final Murray ranked
third with a total score of 61.24 and became the recipient of the National Scholarship for Graduate Students.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Personal profile:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Ma Ruirui, female, a 2019 student majoring in agronomy and seed industry in the College of Agriculture,
Northwest Agriculture and Forestry University. Pass CET4 and Computer Level 2 exam. In June 2021, she will
publish a paper entitled &amp;lsquo;The Transcriptional and Splicing Changes Caused by Hybridization Can Be Globally
Recovered by Genome Doubling during Allopolyploidization&amp;rsquo; in the G1 journal &amp;lsquo;MOLECULAR BIOLOGY AND EVOLUTION&amp;rsquo;
as the second author.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation : Rong Xue</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_7_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_7_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Rong Xue introduced the evolution of wheat and the regulatory mechanism of alternative splicing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation : Tian Lu</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_8_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_8_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Tian Lu introduced the research ideas for the rapid screening of natural mutants of wheat brassinolide, and reported the preliminary analysis results.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation : Pengcheng Wang</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_8_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_8_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Pengcheng Wang reported the relevant results of TaGSK on nitrogen utilization.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation : Xiuyun Ma</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_9_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_9_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In this group meeting, Xiuyun Ma mainly reported the following two parts:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the developed KASP markers to type the RIL population;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Differential analysis of the phenotypes of different genotypes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation : Ruirui Mo</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_9_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_9_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Ruirui Mo introduced the effect of leaf premature senescence on wheat agronomic traits.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly presentcation : Yijin Chen</title>
      <link>/talk/zuhui_10_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/zuhui_10_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Yijin Chen reported the corresponding results of the GWAS analysis of wheat panicle traits, and gradually deepened her understanding of the GWAS analysis of wheat panicle traits in the process of continuous study and research.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meta-analysis of the role of zinc in coordinating absorption of mineral elements in wheat seedlings</title>
      <link>/publication/paper20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/paper20/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BRS1 mediates plant redox regulation and cold responses</title>
      <link>/publication/paper18/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/paper18/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Transcriptional and Splicing Changes Caused by Hybridization Can Be Globally Recovered by Genome Doubling during Allopolyploidization</title>
      <link>/publication/paper19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/paper19/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auxin efflux controls orderly nucellar degeneration and expansion of the female gametophyte in Arabidopsis</title>
      <link>/publication/paper17/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/paper17/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alternative Splicing Diversified the Heat Response and Evolutionary Strategy of Conserved Heat Shock Protein 90s in Hexaploid Wheat (Triticum aestivum L.)</title>
      <link>/publication/paper16/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/paper16/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ph.D. student Junzhe Wang was awarded the Excellence award from the 11th National Youth Forum on Agricultural Biochemistry and Molecular Biology of China.</title>
      <link>/talk/news_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/news_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Main Content:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The &amp;ldquo;19th National Symposium on Agricultural Biochemistry and Molecular Biology&amp;rdquo; hosted by the Agricultural Branch of the Chinese Society of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology was successfully held in Yichun City, Jiangxi Province from November 20 to 23, 2020. Co-organized by the State Key Laboratory of Pest and Disease Biology, organized by Jiangxi Agricultural University and Yichun College.&lt;br/&gt;
The conference organized the 11th Youth Forum, a total of 34 doctoral students and 22 master students participated in the forum exchange competition. Wang Junzhe, a doctoral student in the research group, gave a report on the regulation of plant fertility by the signal molecule nitric oxide in response to adversity stress, and finally won the third prize of the 11th Youth Forum of National Agricultural Biochemistry and Molecular Biology.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ph.D. student Peng Zhao was awarded the 2020 Lixin Tang Scholarship from the Lixin Tang Education Development Fund of Northwest Agriculture and Forestry University.</title>
      <link>/talk/news_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/news_3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Main Content:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In order to encourage students to study diligently, make progress, and cultivate high-quality talents with all-round development of morality, intelligence, body and beauty, the selection activity of &amp;lsquo;Tang Lixin Scholarship&amp;rsquo; established by Mr. Tang Lixin, chairman of Xinshang Group, was officially launched. The college is based on fairness and justice. , the principle of openness, and after strict review and deliberation, Zhao Peng was finally rated as the recipient of the 2020 Tang Lixin Scholarship.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Personal profile:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Peng Zhao, a member of the Communist Party of China, is a 2020-level doctoral candidate in crop genetics and breeding in the College of Agriculture, Northwest Agriculture and Forestry University, under the tutelage of Professor Xu Shengbao. He has won the &amp;lsquo;Top Ten Flag Bearers&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Star Volunteers&amp;rsquo; in the Nanjing Youth Olympic Games, the second prize in the national flag class competition in Jiangsu Province, the &amp;lsquo;Excellent Graduate&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Excellent Student Cadre&amp;rsquo; of Nanjing Agricultural University, and the Agricultural College of Northwest Agriculture and Forestry University. 13 national, provincial and school-level honors including &amp;lsquo;Outstanding Communist Party Member&amp;rsquo;.&lt;br/&gt;
In February 2020, he published &amp;lsquo;Varying Architecture of Heat Shock Elements Contributes to Distinct Magnitudes of Target Gene Expression and Diverged Biological Pathways in Heat Stress Response of Bread Wheat&amp;rsquo; as the first author in &amp;lsquo;Frontiers in Genetics&amp;rsquo; (SCI, Chinese Academy of Sciences District 2) The paper, the impact factor is 3.258; in December 2019, the paper &amp;lsquo;Progress and Prospects of Wheat Heat Resistance Research&amp;rsquo; was published in &amp;lsquo;Journal of Wheat Crops&amp;rsquo; (core B category) as the first author.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19</title>
      <link>/project/covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/covid-19/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating my website to Hugo &#43; Academic &#43; ox-hugo</title>
      <link>/post/migrating/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/migrating/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Being stuck at home during the pandemic, as miserable as it is, actually
helps me to redesign my working environment. One of the many outcomes
is this new personal website powered by the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Academic theme&lt;/a&gt; for 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. I
hope you will agree with me that it just looks awesome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the rest of this blog post, I will explain the workflow to
generate this website. I hope you may find it useful when designing
your own website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#the-hugo-framework&#34;&gt;The Hugo framework&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#static-site-generators&#34;&gt;Static site generators&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#content-management-in-hugo&#34;&gt;Content management in Hugo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#front-matter-in-hugo&#34;&gt;Front matter in Hugo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#hugo-themes&#34;&gt;Hugo themes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#from-markdown-to-html&#34;&gt;From Markdown to HTML&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#the-academic-theme&#34;&gt;The Academic theme&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#content-management-in-academic&#34;&gt;Content management in Academic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#organizing-your-work&#34;&gt;Organizing your work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#widget-pages&#34;&gt;Widget pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#customization-in-academic&#34;&gt;Customization in Academic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#the-ox-hugo-exporter&#34;&gt;The ox-hugo exporter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-hugo-framework&#34;&gt;The Hugo framework&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I admire the front-end web developers who still hand write HTML and
CSS, but those are simply too much for me. If you are like me who just
wants a personal website that can keep track of one&amp;rsquo;s work, chances
are you would like to use some 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web%5Ftemplate%5Fsystem#Static%5Fsite%5Fgenerators&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;static site generator&lt;/a&gt;. When I was young
and had my first encounter with the internet, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsoft%5FFrontPage&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Microsoft Frontpage&lt;/a&gt; and

&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adobe%5FDreamweaver&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dreamweater&lt;/a&gt; were the most popular website generator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;static-site-generators&#34;&gt;Static site generators&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we are well past that time and there are many much better choices
today. One great framework is the &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt;, a lightweight markup
language that is used in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://guides.github.com/features/mastering-markdown/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GitHub readme pages&lt;/a&gt; and deeply integrated
with statistical computing with the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://rmarkdown.rstudio.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;R Markdown&lt;/a&gt;. Many static site
generators (including 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://jekyllrb.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;) are able to automatically
generate HTML codes from Markdown. This is a giant life-saver because
Markdown is so much more readable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some brief research I decided to use Hugo. Based on my reading,
Hugo is renowned as &amp;ldquo;the world&amp;rsquo;s fastest framework for building
websites&amp;rdquo; and many developers were extremely happy about it. But for
me, the killer was two extensions to Hugo: the Academic theme that
implements many use features for academic researchers, and the

&lt;a href=&#34;https://ox-hugo.scripter.co/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ox-hugo&lt;/a&gt; backend that exports &lt;code&gt;.org&lt;/code&gt; files straight to Hugo-compatible
Markdown files. As an academic who already uses Emacs for most of the
day-to-day work, these features are extremely convenient for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Installing Hugo in Mac OS X is straightforward with 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://brew.sh/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;homebrew&lt;/a&gt;. Simply
run&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;brew install hugo
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;content-management-in-hugo&#34;&gt;Content management in Hugo&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s first take a look at how Hugo works. The most useful thing to
know is Hugo&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/content-management/organization/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;organization of content source&lt;/a&gt;. In particular, the most
important is the &lt;code&gt;content&lt;/code&gt; folder, which contains all the Markdown
files needed to generate the website. Here is a sample structure for
the &lt;code&gt;content&lt;/code&gt; folder from Hugo&amp;rsquo;s official documentation (the base URL
for this site is &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/&#34;&gt;https://example.com/&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt;.
└── content
    └── about
    |   └── index.md  // &amp;lt;- https://example.com/about/
    ├── posts
    |   ├── firstpost.md   // &amp;lt;- https://example.com/posts/firstpost/
    |   ├── happy
    |   |   └── ness.md  // &amp;lt;- https://example.com/posts/happy/ness/
    |   └── secondpost.md  // &amp;lt;- https://example.com/posts/secondpost/
    └── quote
        ├── first.md       // &amp;lt;- https://example.com/quote/first/
        └── second.md      // &amp;lt;- https://example.com/quote/second/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, each Markdown file in a directory under &lt;code&gt;content&lt;/code&gt;
generates a webpage. Notice that &lt;code&gt;_index.md&lt;/code&gt; has a special role in
Hugo&amp;mdash;it allows you to add front matter and content to the list
pages. See 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/content-management/organization/#:~:text=%5Findex.md%20has%20a%20special,in%20%5Findex.md%20using%20the%20&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for more detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;front-matter-in-hugo&#34;&gt;Front matter in Hugo&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another important concept is the &lt;em&gt;front matter&lt;/em&gt; of a Markdown file
that contains metadata and options for the content. Some popular
formats are TOML and YAML, which are much more human friendly than
JSON. The following block contains the first few lines of this blog
post. The front matter is the lines between &lt;code&gt;+++&lt;/code&gt; (which means it is in TOML):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-nil&#34;&gt;+++
title = &amp;quot;Migrating website to Hugo + Academic + ox-hugo&amp;quot;
author = [&amp;quot;Qingyuan Zhao&amp;quot;]
date = 2020-06-13
tags = [&amp;quot;Workflow&amp;quot;]
draft = false
+++

Being stuck at home during the pandemic, as miserable as it is, actually
helps me to redesign my working environment....
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from &lt;code&gt;draft&lt;/code&gt; which is a option for the Academic theme, all other
fields are standard for Hugo Markdown files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hugo-themes&#34;&gt;Hugo themes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;cool themes&lt;/a&gt; for Hugo that you can immediately use. As
far as I know, they are useful in two ways. First, all the page
styles are already pre-defined and many of them look awesome! Second,
they also provide convenient templates for the front matter. As an
example, I was initially considering to use the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/hugo-theme-jane/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Jane theme&lt;/a&gt; for this
website. Similar to most other Hugo themes, it is really easy to
install and get started; an example site can be found in its 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/xianmin/hugo-theme-jane/tree/master/exampleSite&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GitHub
repository&lt;/a&gt;, which generates this 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/theme/hugo-theme-jane/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;demo page&lt;/a&gt;. One thing I especially
like about this theme is how it allows the reader to focus on the
website content. Eventually I did not choose it because it is not
powerful enough for all the different functions I needed, but I would
highly recommend it if you just want to write blogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;from-markdown-to-html&#34;&gt;From Markdown to HTML&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After creating all the Markdown content and selecting a theme, you can
preview the website by running&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;hugo server
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;from the website directory. This builds the website and creates a
local web server to
host it. It generates a link (the default is &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/&#34;&gt;http://localhost:1313/&lt;/a&gt;)
which can be pasted into a web browser. In the background, the hugo
server also detects any change to the content and updates the website
automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To public the website, first execute &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; from the website
directory. This builds all the website pages in the &lt;code&gt;public/&lt;/code&gt; folder
within seconds. You can then upload that folder to an FTP server. For
me, this amounts to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;rsync -avz --delete public/ qz280@ssh.maths.cam.ac.uk:~/public_html
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/hosting-and-deployment/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for other options to host and deploy your website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-academic-theme&#34;&gt;The Academic theme&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Academic&lt;/a&gt; is a Hugo theme designed for academic researchers. To me, it
is a website builder with just the right balance of complexity and
flexibility. There are 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/install-locally/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;many ways&lt;/a&gt; to install the Academic theme. I
prefer the Git option by forking and cloning the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-kickstart&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Academic Kickstart
GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;. You can then modify the content of the startup
website and customize its styles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;content-management-in-academic&#34;&gt;Content management in Academic&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Academic has a convenient content management system that is inherited
from Hugo. This is currently how my website directory looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt;├── assets
│   ├── images
│   └── scss
├── config
│   └── _default
├── content
│   ├── authors
│   ├── home
│   ├── news
│   ├── post
│   ├── project
│   ├── publication
│   ├── talk
│   └── teaching
├── content-org
├── data
│   ├── fonts
│   └── themes
├── resources
│   └── _gen
├── scripts
├── static
│   ├── admin
│   ├── files
│   └── img
└── themes
    └── academic
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unsurprisingly, the &lt;code&gt;content&lt;/code&gt; folder contains all the Markdown files
for website content. Most of its sub-directories correspond to a
section of the webpage; in particular, &lt;code&gt;home&lt;/code&gt; corresponds to the
homepage of your website. Another unique folder is the &lt;code&gt;authors&lt;/code&gt;,
which contains basic information about the website owner and all other
authors (not needed for a personal website). The &lt;code&gt;content-org&lt;/code&gt;
contains the org-mode files that generate some or all of the Markdown
files in &lt;code&gt;content&lt;/code&gt;. I will go through this later on in the post, but
it is of course not needed if you don&amp;rsquo;t use org-mode. The &lt;code&gt;config&lt;/code&gt;
folder contains all the important website settings offered by the
Academic theme. See 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/get-started/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;its documentation&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;organizing-your-work&#34;&gt;Organizing your work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A nice feature of the Academic framework is the templates for
publications, talks, projects, and many other academic-related
objects. For example, I recently arXived a paper on the

&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2004.07743&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;selection bias in COVID-19 studies&lt;/a&gt;. To add this new publication to my
webpage, I can execute the following command&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;hugo new --kind publication publication/covid-19-bets
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This generates a Markdown file &lt;code&gt;publication/covid-19-bets/index.md&lt;/code&gt;
with YAML front matter from the publication template. I can then
add all the relevant information about this publication to the
Markdown file. This is how the beginning of this file looks like
right now:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt;---
# Documentation: https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/managing-content/

title: &amp;quot;BETS: The dangers of selection bias in early analyses of the coronavirus disease (COVID-19) pandemic&amp;quot;
authors: [&amp;quot;admin&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Phyllis Ju&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Sergio Bacallado&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Rajen Shah&amp;quot;]
date: 2020-04-16
doi: &amp;quot;&amp;quot;

# Schedule page publish date (NOT publication&#39;s date).
publishDate: 2020-06-13T21:28:45Z

# Publication type.
# Legend: 0 = Uncategorized; 1 = Conference paper; 2 = Journal article;
# 3 = Preprint / Working Paper; 4 = Report; 5 = Book; 6 = Book section;
# 7 = Thesis; 8 = Patent
publication_types: [&amp;quot;3&amp;quot;]
---
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, the YAML fields record important metadata about the
publication, which are used by Academic to automatically generate this
nice 
&lt;a href=&#34;/~qz280/publication/covid-19-bets/&#34;&gt;webpage&lt;/a&gt;. This same workflow apples to talks, projects, and other

&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/managing-content/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;content types&lt;/a&gt; provided by Academic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;widget-pages&#34;&gt;Widget pages&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An important feature of Academic is its 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/page-builder/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;widget pages&lt;/a&gt;. They are
essentially custom page blocks that summarizes the information in the
other pages. By default, the homepage is a widget page with many
built-in widgets:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;&amp;gt; ls content/home
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt;about.md           demo.md            hero.md            projects.md        tags.md
accomplishments.md experience.md      index.md           skills.md          teaching.md
contact.md         featured.md        people.md          slider.md          welcome.md
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I prefer a clean homepage and would use separate section
pages to organize the website. So 
&lt;a href=&#34;/&#34;&gt;my homepage&lt;/a&gt; only contains two
widgets. Additionally, I created a custom widget page called 
&lt;a href=&#34;/news/&#34;&gt;news&lt;/a&gt; to
make announcements and display new content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;customization-in-academic&#34;&gt;Customization in Academic&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The are several important files to modify when building your own
website:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;config/default/config.toml&lt;/code&gt; General configuration for Hugo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;config/default/params.toml&lt;/code&gt; Parameters for Academic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;config/default/menus.toml&lt;/code&gt; Configuration for the menu bar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;content/authors/admin/_index.md&lt;/code&gt; Information about the website
owner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advanced customization can be found 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/customization/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-ox-hugo-exporter&#34;&gt;The ox-hugo exporter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I use &lt;code&gt;ox-hugo&lt;/code&gt;, an Org mode to Hugo exporter, to generate blog
posts and other text-rich content in this website. Since the beginning
of my PhD, I have gradually become an heavy user of the extremely
extensible text editor 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Emacs&lt;/a&gt;. Previously I was mostly just using Emacs
for writing &lt;em&gt;R&lt;/em&gt; and \(\LaTeX\) with the amazing 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ess.r-project.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ESS&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/software/auctex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;AUCTeX&lt;/a&gt; modes. I
saw great reviews of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://orgmode.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Org mode&lt;/a&gt; before and started
to appreciate it as my duties pile up after becoming an independent
investigator. Org mode, as its name suggests, is a great way to keep
oneself organized. Besides keeping notes and managing TODO lists,
Org mode is also great for writing documents. It has powerful backends
that can export &lt;code&gt;.org&lt;/code&gt; files to LaTeX, HTML, Markdown, and other
formats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A picture is worth a thousand words. This is the &lt;code&gt;.org&lt;/code&gt; files that generates the blog
post you are currently viewing.&lt;/p&gt;















&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/~qz280/img/ox-hugo-example.png&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;/~qz280/img/ox-hugo-example.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I followed the &amp;ldquo;one post per Org subtree&amp;rdquo; format 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ox-hugo.scripter.co/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;recommended&lt;/a&gt; by the
&lt;code&gt;ox-hugo&lt;/code&gt; author. So my &lt;code&gt;content-org/&lt;/code&gt; folder has only one &lt;code&gt;.org&lt;/code&gt;
file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;&amp;gt; ls content-org/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt;all-posts.org
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each website section corresponds to a level-1
heading (one *), and each blog post is contained under a level-2
heading in Post. Each heading has some properties (and inherit the
properties of its ancestors) that are exported to TOML or YAML front
matter. If the &lt;code&gt;EXPORT_FILE_NAME&lt;/code&gt; is specified, content under that
heading is then exported to the corresponding section in the &lt;code&gt;content&lt;/code&gt;
folder:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;&amp;gt; ls content/post/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt;_index.md      migrating.md   mr-software.md
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To export all subtrees to Hugo Markdown, simply press &lt;code&gt;C-c C-e H A&lt;/code&gt; in
Emacs. The local Hugo server then picks up the content change and
updates the website. More information about &lt;code&gt;ox-hugo&lt;/code&gt; (including
many advanced features that I am still learning) can be found in its

&lt;a href=&#34;https://ox-hugo.scripter.co/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;online documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s it for now! Feel free to leave a comment below. I will
update this post if I make any major modification to this workflow in
the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Varying Architecture of Heat Shock Elements Contributes to Distinct Magnitudes of Target Gene Expression and Diverged Biological Pathways in Heat Stress Response of Bread Wheat</title>
      <link>/publication/paper15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/paper15/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brassinosteroid Regulates Root Development with Highly Redundant Genes in Hexaploid Wheat</title>
      <link>/publication/paper14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/paper14/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid sequencing reveals insight into heat sensing and signaling of bread wheat</title>
      <link>/publication/paper13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/paper13/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The heat responsive wheat TaRAD23 rescues developmental and thermotolerant defects of the rad23b mutant in Arabidopsis thaliana</title>
      <link>/publication/paper12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/paper12/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolic adaptation of wheat grain contributes to a stable filling rate under heat stress</title>
      <link>/publication/paper11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/paper11/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Add your privacy policy here and set &lt;code&gt;draft: false&lt;/code&gt; to publish it. Otherwise, delete this file if you don&amp;rsquo;t need it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heat stress in filling stage confers distinct effect on starch granules formation in different thermotolerant wheat accessions</title>
      <link>/publication/paper10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/paper10/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolutionary Origin, Gradual Accumulation and Functional Divergence of Heat Shock Factor Gene Family with Plant Evolution</title>
      <link>/publication/paper9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/paper9/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BRS1 Function in Facilitating Lateral Root Emergence in Arabidopsis</title>
      <link>/publication/paper8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/paper8/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VComparative Proteomic Analysis of Flag Leaves Reveals New Insight into Wheat Heat Adaptation</title>
      <link>/publication/paper7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/paper7/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Massive expansion and differential evolution of small heat shock proteins with wheat (Triticum aestivum L.) polyploidization</title>
      <link>/publication/paper6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/paper6/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S-nitrosoglutathione reductases are low-copy number, cysteine-rich proteins in plants that control multiple developmental and defense responses in Arabidopsis</title>
      <link>/publication/paper5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/paper5/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BAK1 directly regulates brassinosteroid perception and BRI1 activation</title>
      <link>/publication/paper4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/paper4/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrated proteomic and cytological study of rice endosperms at the storage phase</title>
      <link>/publication/paper3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/paper3/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic proteomic analysis reveals a switch between central carbon metabolism and alcoholic fermentation in rice filling grains</title>
      <link>/publication/paper2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/paper2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular mapping of QTLs for root response to phosphorus deficiency at seedling stage in wheat (Triticum aestivum L)</title>
      <link>/publication/paper1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/paper1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/featured/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/featured/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
